camerareadycosmetics.com 2019-06-16

# Privacy Policy – Camera Ready Cosmetics

PRIVACY POLICY

Last Update on April 15, 2019. 

This policy describes how Camera Ready Cosmetics™ (referred to as the "Company", "we”, "us", ”our” ) collects, uses, and shares the information we obtain when you visit or make a purchase from camerareadycosmetics.com (the “Site”) or in store.

This privacy policy discusses the “personal information” that Camera Ready Cosmetics obtains from you on camerareadycosmetics.com, and in-store. When we use the term “personal information” we are referring to information that is connected to your name, Device Information or Order Information. This may include things like your e-mail address, mailing address, birthday, telephone number, photographs, personal images, or beauty profile information you provide such as age range, skin tone and type, skin concerns, or information about the products you purchase when those pieces of data are stored with your name. Any information that is not connected to your name, Device Information or Order Information is not considered personal information.

This privacy policy does not cover information that you submit on other websites, even if we communicate with you on those sites. For example, if you post something on Facebook, Twitter, or YouTube, that information is governed by the privacy policies on those websites, and is not governed by this policy.

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

    \- “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

    \- “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps. Example Google Analytics

    \- “Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site. Example Google Analytics, Facebook Pixel, and Adroll to track customer behavior.

Additionally when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card numbers, Apple Pay, Google Pay, Amazon Pay, PayPal, Afterpay, email address, and phone number.  We refer to this information as “Order Information.”

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only the consumer's domain name, but not the e-mail address (where possible). We collect only the domain name, but not the email address of visitors to our Web page, aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit, information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations.

The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Web page, used to customize the content and/or layout of our page for each individual visitor, used to notify consumers about updates to our Web site, used by us to contact consumers for marketing purposes, not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes, disclosed when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Website and applicable laws or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web site, to a successor entity in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, sale of assets or other corporate change respecting the Web site.

With respect to cookies: We use cookies to record session information, including but not limited to website activity, items that visitors add to their shopping cart, and IP addresses. Our store also uses Pinterest Tag, Google, Facebook Pixel, and Adroll to track customer behavior.

If you supply us with your postal address online you will only receive the information for which you provided us your address. Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers online will only receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed online.

With respect to Ad Servers: We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies.

Customers may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by emailing us. Upon request, we provide site visitors with access to unique identifier information (e.g., customer number or password) that we maintain about them, transaction information (e.g., dates on which customers made purchases, amounts and types of purchases) that we maintain about them. Consumers can access this information by sending us an email.

Upon request, we offer visitors the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact information, unique identifiers, and transaction information. Consumers can have this information corrected by sending us an email. With respect to security: We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

We do collect email addresses from orders to send occasional sale information. We do not sell or release any email address on this list. To be removed from this list please contact us.

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed in this policy.  Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to Canada and the United States.

PRIVACY STATEMENT

SECTION 1.A -  **WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

When you purchase something from our store, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address, phone number, and email address.

We use the Order Information that we collect generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations).  Additionally, we use this Order Information to:

Communicate with you;

Screen our orders for potential risk or fraud; and when in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

When you browse our store, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.

Email marketing (if applicable): With your permission, we may send you emails about our store, new products and other updates.

Camera Ready Cosmetics primarily uses the personal information that it collects to provide you with products, information, and services. We may use your information to track your purchase history and to contact you for account and promotional purposes. We may also use your personal information for other legitimate business purposes, including to detect and prevent fraud, to collect amounts owing to us and to maintain business records.

SECTION 1.B -  **SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above.  For example, we use Shopify to power our online store--you can read more about how Shopify uses your Personal Information here:  https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy.  We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site--you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here:  https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/.  You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here:  https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

For example:

We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy>/.  

You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here:  <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

We use Zaius to send email messages, marketing material, and newsletters.  You can read more about how Zaius uses your personal information here: <https://www.zaius.com/privacy-policy/> or opt out here: <https://app.zaius.com/opt_out>

We use Facebook for advertising and promotion. [ See Behavioural Advertising Below ]

You can read more about how Facebook uses your personal information here: <https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/update> . You can adjust your Facebook Ad settings here:  <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads>

We use Pinterest for advertising and promotion. You can read more about how Pinterest uses your personal information here: <https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy> . You can adjust your Pinterest settings here:  <https://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalization-and-data>

You can read more about how Twitter uses your personal information here: <https://gdpr.twitter.com/en.html> . You can adjust your Twitter Ad settings here:  <https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads>

**BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING**

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you.  For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by:

  * FACEBOOK - <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads>
  * GOOGLE - <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous>
  * PINTEREST: <https://help.pinterest.com/en/articles/personalization-and-data>
  * TWITTER: <https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads>
  * ADROLL: <https://app.adroll.com/optout>
  * ZAIUS: <https://app.zaius.com/opt_out>

You can opt-out of some, but not all, online behavioral based advertising by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) or by using your browser settings to block cookies or notify you when a cookie is set.

SECTION 2 -  **CONSENT**

How do you get my consent?

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

How do I withdraw my consent?

If after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at any time, by contacting us at service@crcmakeup.com or mailing us at: Camera Ready Cosmetics 14203 Proton Rd, Dallas, TX, 75244, United States

You can opt-out of some, but not all, online behavioral based advertising by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) or by using your browser settings to block cookies or notify you when a cookie is set.

SECTION 3 -  **DISCLOSURE**

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service.

SECTION 4 -  **SHOPIFY**

Our store is hosted on Shopify Inc. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through Shopify’s data storage, databases, and the general Shopify application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

 **Payment:  **If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Shopify stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

For more insight, you may also want to read Shopify’s Terms of Service here or Privacy Statement here.

**Cookies:  **Here is a list of cookies that we use. We’ve listed them here so you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not.

_session_id, unique token, sessional, Allows Shopify to store information about your session (referrer, landing page, etc).

_shopify_visit, no data held, Persistent for 30 minutes from the last visit, Used by our website provider’s internal stats tracker to record the number of visits

_shopify_uniq, no data held, expires midnight (relative to the visitor) of the next day, Counts the number of visits to a store by a single customer.

cart, unique token, persistent for 2 weeks, Stores information about the contents of your cart.

_secure_session_id, unique token, sessional

storefront_digest, unique token, indefinite If the shop has a password, this is used to determine if the current visitor has access.

SECTION 5 -  **THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located in a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

 **Links:**

When you click on links on our store, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements.

You can opt-out of some, but not all, online behavioral based advertising by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) or by using your browser settings to block cookies or notify you when a cookie is set.

SECTION 6 -  **SECURITY**

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

We realize that our customers trust us to protect their personal information. We take that task seriously and maintain reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to help protect your personal information. While we attempt to protect the information in our possession, no security system is perfect and we cannot promise that information about you will remain secure in all circumstances.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

SECTION 7 -  **AGE OF CONSENT**

By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

SECTION 8 -  **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web site periodically.

If our store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you. 

QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at service@crcmakeup.com or by mail at Camera Ready Cosmetics

[Re: Privacy Compliance Officer]

[14203 Proton Rd, Dallas, TX, 75244, United States]
